<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Siemens Ltd on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/siemens-ltd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Siemens Ltd on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/siemens-ltd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Siemens Ltd - Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/siemens-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/siemens-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Detailed Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis looks into Siemens Limited&amp;rsquo;s Annual Report for FY2023-24, examining its financial performance, business segments, identified risks, and ESG (Environmental, Social, and Governance) initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Financial Performance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The report shows strong financial performance in FY2024 despite global economic headwinds. Key highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Revenue from operations increased significantly to ₹204,966 million (14.4% growth) compared to ₹179,651 million in FY2023.  This growth is noteworthy considering the global economic slowdown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profitability:&lt;/strong&gt;  Profit Before Tax (PBT) rose substantially by 38.2% to ₹35,177 million, and Profit After Tax (PAT) increased by 39.4% to ₹26,651 million.  Operating profit margins improved to 12.6% from 11.4% in FY2023.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order Intake:&lt;/strong&gt; While new orders received decreased by 49.2% to ₹235,641 million compared to FY2023, this is largely attributed to a large, one-off order in the previous year. Excluding this, new orders showed a 14% increase, indicating sustained demand.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividend:&lt;/strong&gt; The Board recommended a dividend of ₹12 per share (600% of face value), a significant increase from ₹10 in the previous year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return on Metrics:&lt;/strong&gt; Return on Net Worth (RONW) improved significantly to 17.48% (FY23: 14.67%), and Return on Capital Employed (ROCE) also grew to 23.07% (FY23: 19.54%).  These figures demonstrate efficient capital utilization and strong profitability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. Business Segments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
