<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Avalon Technologies Ltd on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/avalon-technologies-ltd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Avalon Technologies Ltd on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/avalon-technologies-ltd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avalon Technologies Ltd: Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/avalon-technologies-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/avalon-technologies-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;comprehensive-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Comprehensive Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#comprehensive-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis delves into the 2023-24 Annual Report of Avalon Technologies Limited, covering its financial performance, business segments, risk factors, and ESG initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Financial Performance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Avalon&amp;rsquo;s FY2023-24 consolidated financial results show a mixed picture, largely impacted by macroeconomic headwinds in its key US market.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated revenue decreased by 8.2% YoY to INR 867 crore, primarily due to a 16% drop in US revenue (destocking by US clients).  Indian operations, accounting for 77% of revenue (INR 670 crore), remained robust and profitable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profitability:&lt;/strong&gt;  Lower revenue and higher fixed costs negatively impacted operating leverage. EBITDA fell by 44.5% YoY to INR 62 crore (7.2% margin), while PAT decreased by 46.7% to INR 28 crore (3.2% margin).  Indian operations maintained strong EBITDA (12.7%) and PAT (8.5%) margins.  US operations reported a post-tax loss of INR 30 crore.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order Book:&lt;/strong&gt; Despite the challenges, the order book increased by 11% YoY to INR 1,366 crore (executable over 14 months). Long-term contracts showed significant growth (58% YoY) reaching INR 949 crore, providing good revenue visibility for the next 2-3 years.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity:&lt;/strong&gt; Avalon maintained a strong cash position (INR 118 crore at year-end), with INR 50 crore earmarked for debt repayment in the US subsidiary.  Existing working capital lines (INR 185 crore) provide flexibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Financial Ratios:&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROCE:&lt;/strong&gt; Declined significantly to 10% (from 24.6% in FY2023), mainly due to lower revenues and increased equity from the IPO.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset Turnover:&lt;/strong&gt; 8.3x, indicating efficient asset utilization (though slightly down from 10.4x).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net Debt/EBITDA:&lt;/strong&gt; -0.3x (significantly improved from 2.7x), reflecting debt repayment from IPO proceeds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inventory Days:&lt;/strong&gt; Increased to 118 days (from 106 days), partially due to lower revenue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Receivables Days:&lt;/strong&gt; Slightly improved to 79 days (from 80 days).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payables Days:&lt;/strong&gt; Decreased to 36 days (from 41 days).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net Working Capital Days:&lt;/strong&gt; Increased to 161 days (from 145 days).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. Business Segments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
