<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stylam Industries Ltd on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/stylam-industries-ltd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stylam Industries Ltd on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/stylam-industries-ltd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stylam Industries Ltd - Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/stylam-industries-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/stylam-industries-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Detailed Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis looks into the Stylam Industries Limited annual report for FY2023-24, examining its financial performance, business segments, risk factors, and ESG initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Financial Performance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FY2023-24 showed a mixed bag for Stylam. While profitability metrics improved significantly, revenue declined slightly.  This suggests a successful cost optimization and efficiency drive, but also hints at challenges in the external market.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue:&lt;/strong&gt; Decreased marginally by 4% to ₹914 crore from ₹952 crore in FY2022-23. This dip is attributed to global headwinds including the Russia-Ukraine war, inflation, and tepid demand, impacting both export and domestic sales.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EBITDA:&lt;/strong&gt;  Increased significantly by 18% to ₹183 crore from ₹155 crore, demonstrating successful cost management. EBITDA margin improved substantially to 20% from 16%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAT:&lt;/strong&gt; Rose by 34% to ₹128 crore from ₹96 crore, highlighting improved profitability despite lower revenue.  The PAT margin increased to 14% from 10%.  A significant portion of this increase seems due to a reduction in finance costs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt:&lt;/strong&gt; The company achieved a significant milestone by becoming debt-free in FY2024, strengthening its balance sheet and providing greater financial flexibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return on Equity (ROE):&lt;/strong&gt;  Decreased to 20% from 23%, potentially influenced by the increased equity due to retained earnings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return on Capital Employed (ROCE):&lt;/strong&gt; Remained relatively stable around 30%, indicating efficient capital utilization.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest Coverage Ratio:&lt;/strong&gt; Showed dramatic improvement, rising to 66.87 from 16.6, reflecting the debt-free status.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Export Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; Exports remained a major revenue driver, contributing ₹611 crore (67% of total revenue).  While overall revenue declined, export sales showed resilience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. Business Segments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
