<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DiGiSPICE Technologies Limited on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/digispice-technologies-limited/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DiGiSPICE Technologies Limited on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/digispice-technologies-limited/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DiGiSPICE Technologies Limited: Q3 FY25 Earnings Call Transcript Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/digispice-technologies-limited2025-02-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/digispice-technologies-limited2025-02-17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;financial-performance&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Financial Performance&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#financial-performance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue:&lt;/strong&gt; Revenue grew 7% quarter-on-quarter and 2% year-on-year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gross Margin:&lt;/strong&gt; Increased by 3% from Rs. 43 crores to Rs. 44 crores quarter-on-quarter, a 5% increase year-on-year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EBITDA:&lt;/strong&gt; Improved from (-3.2) crores to (-1.9) crores.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EBIT:&lt;/strong&gt; Moved from Rs. 40 lakhs to Rs. 2.8 crores.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAT (Continuing Business):&lt;/strong&gt; Positive in the current quarter at almost Rs. 1 crore, compared to Rs. (-1.5) crores in the previous quarter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer GTV:&lt;/strong&gt; Increased by 16% quarter-on-quarter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GM Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; 2% quarter-on-quarter and 5% year-on-year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;And consequently, the gross margin has increased by 3% from Rs. 43 crores to Rs.44 crores.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;EBITDA has improved due to the gross margin and some bit of reduction in indirect costs from (-3.2) crores to (-1.9) crores&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Strategic Initiatives &amp;amp; Business Updates&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spice Pay (UPI):&lt;/strong&gt; Launched, aiming to onboard consumers onto UPI using a prepaid instrument wallet. &amp;ldquo;We have launched our Spice Pay product that I will talk to you briefly about today, which is our entry to UPI.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NBFC Acquisition:&lt;/strong&gt; In process, aiming to create credit products for the merchant base and MSMEs. &amp;ldquo;We are in the process of working with the regulator to look at a strategic NBFC acquisition from within the group.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amalgamation:&lt;/strong&gt; Spice Money (subsidiary) to be merged into DiGiSPICE Technologies. &amp;ldquo;Our subsidiary which is Spice Money, our FinTech business, will get merged into DiGiSPICE Technologies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collections Business:&lt;/strong&gt; Significant growth, contributing approximately 46% to 47% of total volumes. &amp;ldquo;Collections as a part of our business is now contributing approximately 46% to 47% of total volumes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CASA:&lt;/strong&gt; Opening over 2,000 accounts a day. &amp;ldquo;Currently, we are opening over 2,000 accounts a day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secured Loans:&lt;/strong&gt; Focusing on secured loan distribution with multiple partners. &amp;ldquo;We have now started focusing majorly on the secured loans and on secured loan distribution with multiple partners.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Market &amp;amp; Competitive Landscape&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AePS Market Share:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintained market leadership in the Aadhaar-enabled payment system business, with a market share of above 17%. &amp;ldquo;We at Spice Money have a leading market share of 17%, and we have held this.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPI Expansion:&lt;/strong&gt; Aiming to expand the UPI consumer base by bringing in another 300 million users. &amp;ldquo;There is an opportunity to bring in another 300 million to the UPI platform.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on Bharat:&lt;/strong&gt; Targeting unmet formal financial needs of Bharat using technology. &amp;ldquo;DiGiSPICE is now a very focused fintech company, and we are focused on meeting the unmet formal financial needs of Bharat using technology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Risk Factors &amp;amp; Challenges&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GST Notice:&lt;/strong&gt; Received a GST notice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fraud:&lt;/strong&gt; Concern about fraud in financially vulnerable areas. &amp;ldquo;We are working in a part of India that&amp;rsquo;s very financially vulnerable. So, we have to make sure that we stay on top of it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Forward-Looking Statements&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPI Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Focus on building a strong UPI business. &amp;ldquo;And this is something that we will keep you updated as we go forward. It&amp;rsquo;s one of our big strategic goals going forward.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credit Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Credit is seen as the next growth engine. &amp;ldquo;So, we are taking this journey forward and credit is going to be definitely the next growth engine for us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FinTech Focus:&lt;/strong&gt; Committed to becoming a pure fintech company. &amp;ldquo;And that is why we have said we will focus on becoming a pure fintech company and growing our business in this space.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;qa-insights&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Q&amp;amp;A Insights&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#qa-insights&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AePS Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Focus on innovation, new products, compliance, and self-regulation to strengthen AePS position.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMS Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Resulting from a combination of growth in large SMEs and increased business per enterprise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact of 2FA:&lt;/strong&gt; The impact of 2FA on AePS volumes has waived off. &amp;ldquo;So, I think the impact of 2FA has kind of waived off once it&amp;rsquo;s been removed from a per transaction basis to just the first transaction of the day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Float Income:&lt;/strong&gt; The float balances on the accounts have grown to over 130 crores.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Margin Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; Driven by product mix, with collections being a lower-margin product.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Management Tone &amp;amp; Sentiment&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confident:&lt;/strong&gt; About building a strong business in the UPI space.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Committed:&lt;/strong&gt; To leveraging AI and technology to drive down costs and increase service reach.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focused:&lt;/strong&gt; On digital financial inclusion in Bharat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;button-container&#34;&gt;    &#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bseindia.com/xml-data/corpfiling/AttachHis/100fa3b1-86c5-402d-9535-3b06c09e1b5b.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; class=&#34;report-button&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Download Transcript&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
