<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Suprajit Engineering Limited on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/suprajit-engineering-limited/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Suprajit Engineering Limited on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/suprajit-engineering-limited/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Suprajit Engineering Limited: Q3 FY25 Earnings Call</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/suprajit-engineering-limited-q3-fy25-earnings-call2025-02-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/suprajit-engineering-limited-q3-fy25-earnings-call2025-02-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;earnings-call-transcript-analysis-report&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Earnings Call Transcript Analysis Report&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#earnings-call-transcript-analysis-report&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;financial-performance&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Financial Performance&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#financial-performance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue (Consolidated excluding SCS, 9 months ended Dec 2024):&lt;/strong&gt; INR 2,290 crores vs. INR 2,113 crores (previous year), +8%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational EBITDA (Consolidated excluding SCS, 9 months ended Dec 2024):&lt;/strong&gt; INR 295 crores vs. INR 231 crores (previous year), +28%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue (Standalone, 9 months ended Dec 2024):&lt;/strong&gt; INR 1,283 crores vs. INR 1,124 crores, +14%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational EBITDA (Standalone, 9 months ended Dec 2024):&lt;/strong&gt; INR 226 crores vs. INR 200 crores (previous year), +13%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue (Consolidated excluding SCS, Quarter ended Dec 2024):&lt;/strong&gt; INR 782 crores vs. INR 724 crores, +8%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational EBITDA (Consolidated excluding SCS, Quarter ended Dec 2024):&lt;/strong&gt; INR 111 crores vs. INR 87 crores, +28%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt:&lt;/strong&gt; Total debt level of INR 627 crores as of December 31, 2024.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cash Surplus:&lt;/strong&gt; INR 276 crores invested in mutual funds and bonds as of December 31, 2024.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCD EBITDA:&lt;/strong&gt; Achieved double-digit EBITDA margin of 11.8% in Q3.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective Tax Rate Guidance:&lt;/strong&gt; Expect around 26-27% for the year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Strategic Initiatives &amp;amp; Business Updates&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suprajit Controls Division (SCD):&lt;/strong&gt; Achieved 5% revenue growth and EBITDA surged over 100%. &amp;ldquo;Driven by new contracts and better plant performance and also, of course, the restructuring that SAL, that is the export-oriented unit in India and also the U-9, which is again a EOU in India.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domestic Cable Division (DCD):&lt;/strong&gt; Continuing to grow profitably, expanding in aftermarket and &amp;ldquo;theme beyond cables&amp;rdquo;, specifically STC products and braking projects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phoenix Division:&lt;/strong&gt; PLD margins performed well. Exports at Luxlite experienced volatility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suprajit Electronics Division (SED):&lt;/strong&gt; Won a throttle project from a leading EV 2-wheeler customer. Secured global off-highway electronic projects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suprajit Technology Center (STC):&lt;/strong&gt; Showcased products at Bharat Mobility Expo, attracted interest in actuators, braking, and sensor product lines.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCS Acquisition:&lt;/strong&gt; Integration and turnaround phase. Restructuring costs due to operational inefficiencies related to the relocation of operations to Morocco.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morocco Operations:&lt;/strong&gt; Moving from a 3-shift to a 1-shift operation, showcasing productivity improvements. Strong team in Morocco adapting to Suprajit&amp;rsquo;s expectations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poland Plant Closure:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Poland plant will soon be closed&amp;hellip;will be completely closed in the coming 2 quarters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;German Warehouse Relocation:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Germany warehouse will be shifted to a location very close to Suprajit Hungary, so the Suprajit Hungary team will take a lead in supporting those operations rather than let it have sitting in Germany.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCS Canada and China Acquisition:&lt;/strong&gt; Expected to close in Q4 or early Q1 of next year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Market &amp;amp; Competitive Landscape&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indian Automotive Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;It was not up to the expectations&amp;rdquo; with flat passenger vehicle growth and moderate 2-wheeler growth. Industry grew around 10% for the 9 months as of December 2024.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. Market:&lt;/strong&gt; Political stability, but questions remain regarding ICE vs. EV leadership and treatment of OEMs that moved to Mexico and had purchasing offices in China.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;European Market:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Continues to flounder&amp;rdquo; with political indecisiveness and lack of economic stability. Manpower cuts at OEMs, production cuts, and economic brinkmanship.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China:&lt;/strong&gt; Market expansion in Europe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red Sea and Panama Canal:&lt;/strong&gt; Continuing to impact the industry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cable Exports:&lt;/strong&gt; Indian cable exports grew by 35%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wescon:&lt;/strong&gt; Non-automotive business had a degrowth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electric Vehicle Market:&lt;/strong&gt; EV market in India was &amp;ldquo;quite tumultuous&amp;rdquo; impacting margins due to product mix changes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Risk Factors &amp;amp; Challenges&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCS:&lt;/strong&gt; Impacted by the shrinking European market and restructuring costs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Matamoros, Mexico:&lt;/strong&gt; Challenges related to tariffs and labor costs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suprajit Electronics Division:&lt;/strong&gt; Margins impacted by product mix changes due to shifts in EV market volumes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Market Uncertainties:&lt;/strong&gt; Political and economic instability in the U.S. and Europe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tariffs:&lt;/strong&gt; Potential impact of tariffs, especially on Matamoros operations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Labor Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; High labor costs in Matamoros.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supply Chain Issues:&lt;/strong&gt; France-based supplier was &amp;ldquo;creating a lot of problems for Matamoros as a part of the supply chain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Forward-Looking Statements&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCS Turnaround:&lt;/strong&gt; Expects to see &amp;ldquo;fruits of this turnaround project in the coming quarters&amp;rdquo; and improvements in the next few quarters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morocco Operations:&lt;/strong&gt; Expect to see &amp;ldquo;how we have moved literally almost, I would say, conquered the Western world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Expects the growth of SAL Automotive to be &amp;ldquo;even more exciting&amp;rdquo; with multiple new contracts going into production.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCD Margins:&lt;/strong&gt; Aims to improve and consolidate current achievements. &amp;ldquo;But of course, our journey to further improve and consolidate this what we have achieved in this quarter is paramount importance for us.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capacity Utilization:&lt;/strong&gt; Significant capacities available and will be utilized as needed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electronics Division Margins:&lt;/strong&gt; Expects utilization to build up and &amp;ldquo;get back to the double digit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;qa-insights&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Q&amp;amp;A Insights&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#qa-insights&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCD Margin Improvement:&lt;/strong&gt; Driven by key plants performing well (SAL, SEU, Lone Star, Hungary, Wescon, Unit9), except Matamoros.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motor Sourcing from India:&lt;/strong&gt; Shift expected to reduce overall acquisition costs and eliminate supply chain pain points.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCS EBITDA Positive Visibility:&lt;/strong&gt; Restructuring is underway, Morocco plant is strategically located. Expect stabilization and improved performance over the next few quarters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective Tax Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; High in Q3 due to tax on redemption of mutual funds and bonds, but expected to be around 26-27% for the year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wescon Business Outlook:&lt;/strong&gt; Expects some amount of perking up.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Management Tone &amp;amp; Sentiment&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall Tone:&lt;/strong&gt; Positive about growth both on a standalone and on consol basis (excluding SCS). Confident about SCD turnaround.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caution:&lt;/strong&gt; Acknowledged challenges in the European market. Cautious about the turnaround of SCS and uncertainties in the global market.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confident:&lt;/strong&gt; Emphasized the strategic positioning of the Morocco plant and the ability to offer flexible solutions to customers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;key-takeaways&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Key Takeaways&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#key-takeaways&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Suprajit Engineering has demonstrated solid financial performance, driven by both domestic and international operations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The company&amp;rsquo;s strategic focus on operational efficiency, restructuring, and diversification is expected to drive future growth and profitability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While the European market and SCS acquisition pose challenges, management is confident in the long-term potential of these initiatives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The company&amp;rsquo;s flexible manufacturing capabilities and strategic location in Morocco provide a competitive advantage in navigating global uncertainties and tariffs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;button-container&#34;&gt;    &#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bseindia.com/xml-data/corpfiling/AttachHis/ffa16f40-efb2-4a69-91ba-36d6ca3312a4.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; class=&#34;report-button&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Download Transcript&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
