<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patel Engineering Ltd on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/patel-engineering-ltd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patel Engineering Ltd on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/patel-engineering-ltd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Patel Engineering Ltd: Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/patel-engineering-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/patel-engineering-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;comprehensive-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Comprehensive Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#comprehensive-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis delves into Patel Engineering Ltd.&amp;rsquo;s (PEL) Annual Report for FY2023-24, covering financial performance, business segments, risk factors, and ESG initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Financial Performance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PEL demonstrated robust financial growth in FY24, building on the positive momentum of recent years.  Key highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Revenue Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated revenue from operations increased by 16.78% YoY to ₹45,441.08 million, while standalone revenue grew by 15.59% to ₹44,120.39 million.  This growth reflects strong execution across various projects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Profitability:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated Operating EBITDA increased by 22.92% YoY to ₹6,902.94 million, and standalone Operating EBITDA grew by 14.73% to ₹6,201.05 million.  This indicates improved operational efficiency and margin expansion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Substantial Net Profit Increase:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated net profit surged by 70.60% YoY to ₹2,641.00 million, with standalone net profit rising by 84.90% to ₹2,881.80 million. This reflects improved profitability and debt reduction efforts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EPS Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Basic EPS from continuing operations increased to ₹3.64, indicating enhanced shareholder value.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt Reduction:&lt;/strong&gt; While gross debt increased slightly to ₹18,855 million, the company actively reduced its net serviceable debt by ₹3,310 million, primarily through settlement of arbitration awards under the Vivad Se Vishwas scheme (₹1,300 million) and an international arbitration award (₹1,500 million in Q1 FY25).  A further ₹4,000 million was raised through a Qualified Institutional Placement (QIP) in Q1 FY25, aimed at further debt reduction and working capital improvement.  Credit rating upgrades from BBB+ to A- reflect this improved financial position.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. Business Segments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
