<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Southern Petrochemicals Industries Corporation Ltd on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/southern-petrochemicals-industries-corporation-ltd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Southern Petrochemicals Industries Corporation Ltd on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/southern-petrochemicals-industries-corporation-ltd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Southern Petrochemicals Industries Corporation Ltd - Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/southern-petrochemicals-industries-corporation-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/southern-petrochemicals-industries-corporation-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Detailed Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis looks into the 2023-24 annual report of Southern Petrochemical Industries Corporation Limited (SPIC), covering its financial performance, business segments, risks, and ESG (Environmental, Social, and Governance) initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Financial Performance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SPIC&amp;rsquo;s financial year 2023-24 shows a significant decline in overall performance compared to the previous year.  Key financial highlights:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue from Operations:&lt;/strong&gt; A substantial drop from ₹2,828.82 crore in 2022-23 to ₹1,943.86 crore in 2023-24. This is primarily attributed to lower production due to plant machinery disturbances and flooding caused by Cyclone Michaung.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net Profit:&lt;/strong&gt; A sharp decrease from ₹284.44 crore to ₹87.91 crore. This decline reflects the impact of lower production and increased costs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profitability Ratios:&lt;/strong&gt;  The Net Profit Ratio decreased from 10.09% to 4.55%, indicating reduced profitability.  The Debt Service Coverage Ratio plummeted from 2.46 times to 0.89 times, raising concerns about the company&amp;rsquo;s ability to service its debt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividend:&lt;/strong&gt; The Board recommended a dividend of ₹1.50 per share (15% of face value), subject to shareholder approval. This is consistent with the previous year, despite the significant drop in profitability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt:&lt;/strong&gt; SPIC raised ₹50 crore through a private placement of debentures during September 2023.  The company&amp;rsquo;s overall debt level and the impact of increased interest rates are essential factors to monitor in future reports.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. Business Segments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
