<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tata Consultancy Services Ltd on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/tata-consultancy-services-ltd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tata Consultancy Services Ltd on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/tata-consultancy-services-ltd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tata Consultancy Services Ltd:Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/tata-consultancy-services-ltdannual-report-2023-24-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/tata-consultancy-services-ltdannual-report-2023-24-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;comprehensive-performance-overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Comprehensive Performance Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#comprehensive-performance-overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;3-year-trend-analysis-of-key-financial-metrics&#34;&gt;&#xA;  3-Year Trend Analysis of Key Financial Metrics&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#3-year-trend-analysis-of-key-financial-metrics&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated revenue growth has decelerated significantly, from 17.6% (FY23) to 6.8% (FY24). Constant currency revenue growth for FY24 was 3.4%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profitability:&lt;/strong&gt; Operating margin (EBIT margin before other income) improved to 24.6% in FY24 from 24.1% in FY23. Net margin also increased to 19.3% in FY24.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earnings Per Share:&lt;/strong&gt; Earnings per share showed a CAGR of 9%&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cash Conversion:&lt;/strong&gt; OCF as a percentage of total revenue decreased slightly to 18.7% of revenue, with Free Cash Flow accounting for 94.1% of OCF.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shareholder Payout:&lt;/strong&gt; Increased by 12.8% reaching 47,445 cr.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&amp;amp;D Spend:&lt;/strong&gt; Increased by 10% but remained at 1.1% of total revenue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;business-segment-performance&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Business Segment Performance&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#business-segment-performance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BFSI:&lt;/strong&gt; Showed moderate growth of 5.6% (FY24), with a stable segment margin of 25.9%. The demand was for customer journey transformation, payment modernization, new products, core system transformation, and GenAI/AI for personalization and fraud detection.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication, Media, and Technology (CMT):&lt;/strong&gt; Growth was 4.6% (FY24) with a segment margin decrease to 27.7% from 28.3%. Key drivers were 5G and fiber rollout, digital product innovation, and GenAI.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consumer Business:&lt;/strong&gt; Grew by 4.9% (FY24) with a margin of 26.0%, slightly up from 25.7% due to demand in marketplace, social commerce, smart checkout, and resilient supply chains.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life Sciences and Healthcare:&lt;/strong&gt; Grew 8.7% (FY24) , with the segment margin improved to 28.5% from 28.0%. Demand was driven by modernization of clinical landscape, digital twins for manufacturing, and GenAI for knowledge synthesis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manufacturing:&lt;/strong&gt; Showed strong growth of 10.6% (FY24), with a significant margin increase to 30.9%. Demand was linked to sustainable fuels, transportation, connected autonomous vehicles, battery technology, and electric vehicles.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Others:&lt;/strong&gt; This segment experienced the highest growth at 14.5% (FY24) and improved segment margin from 21.1% to 22.3%. Growth was fueled by renewable energy integrations and asset performance management.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geographical revenue:&lt;/strong&gt; Growth was led by emerging market. Latin America grew by 21.1%, and India grew by 20.3%&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;major-strategic-initiatives-and-their-progress&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Major Strategic Initiatives and Their Progress&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#major-strategic-initiatives-and-their-progress&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI and Cloud Focus:&lt;/strong&gt; The creation of the AI.Cloud unit consolidates expertise. Over 300,000 employees were upskilled in GenAI technologies in FY24. Key partnerships were made with hyperscalers and other AI ecosystem players. TCS WisdomNext platform launched.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Energy Transition:&lt;/strong&gt; Investments in research on green hydrogen, biofuels, and digital platforms. Proprietary ESG framework developed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5G/6G Communication:&lt;/strong&gt; TCS is engineering 5G/6G communication stacks and setting up labs for communication infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talent Upskilling:&lt;/strong&gt; Significant focus on upskilling in areas like Cloud, AI, and Cyber Security. 51 million learning hours logged and nearly 5 million competencies acquired by employees.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability:&lt;/strong&gt; TCS is on track to become net zero by 2045. They are well ahead of their initial scope 1 and 2, targetting 70% reduction by 2025, by already acheiving 80% reduction in FY24.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nation Building Projects:&lt;/strong&gt; TCS and partners enabling BSNL to enhance competitiveness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;risk-landscape-changes&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Risk Landscape Changes&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#risk-landscape-changes&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macroeconomic and Geopolitical Volatility:&lt;/strong&gt; Continued uncertainty impacted client decision-making, increasing the focus on cost optimization and cloud transformation projects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talent Acquisition and Retention:&lt;/strong&gt; Short supply of emerging technical skills is a persistent challenge.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cybersecurity:&lt;/strong&gt; Risks have increased due to evolving threats and geopolitical factors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Protection:&lt;/strong&gt; Growing focus on data protection and compliance, especially with the rise of GenAI, increases regulatory risk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;esg-initiatives-and-metrics&#34;&gt;&#xA;  ESG Initiatives and Metrics&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#esg-initiatives-and-metrics&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environmental:&lt;/strong&gt; TCS reduced its Scope 1 and 2 emissions by 80% in FY24 (vs. 2016 baseline). Renewable energy use increased to 74% of total energy use. Freshwater consumption was reduced.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social:&lt;/strong&gt; Workforce diversity includes 152 nationalities, with women representing 35.6% of employees. Significant investment in employee training, with 51 million learning hours and 5 million competencies acquired. CSR spend was &amp;rsquo; 953 crore, impacting 7.1 million beneficiaries.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governance:&lt;/strong&gt; High standards of corporate governance are embedded. Compliance framework and governance structure aligned with global ESG standards.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;management-outlook&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Management Outlook&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#management-outlook&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The company anticipates continued deal flow and pipeline velocity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greater opportunities are foreseen as businesses become more technology-intensive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The medium to long-term growth outlook is positive due to strong client relationships and the large order book (US$ 42.7 billion).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Near-term uncertainty remains, with potential moderation in growth for FY25 if delayed decision-making persists.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Detailed Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;financial-position-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Financial Position Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#financial-position-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;3-year-comparative-analysis-of-assets-liabilities-and-equity-standalone&#34;&gt;&#xA;  3-Year Comparative Analysis of Assets, Liabilities, and Equity (Standalone)&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#3-year-comparative-analysis-of-assets-liabilities-and-equity-standalone&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(₹ crore)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
