<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zomato Ltd on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/zomato-ltd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zomato Ltd on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/zomato-ltd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zomato Ltd - Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/zomato-ltd-fy-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/zomato-ltd-fy-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Detailed Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a detailed analysis of the provided Zomato Limited Annual Report for FY24 (ending March 31, 2024).  The report showcases significant growth and a transition to profitability, but also highlights key risks and ongoing ESG commitments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Financial Highlights:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The report presents both GAAP and non-GAAP (Adjusted) financial metrics.  Key takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strong Revenue Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated Adjusted Revenue surged by 56% YoY to INR 13,545 crore.  This growth was driven across all business segments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profitability Achieved:&lt;/strong&gt;  Consolidated business turned profitable for the first time. Consolidated Adjusted EBITDA reached INR 372 crore (compared to a loss of INR 783 crore in FY23).  Consolidated PAT was INR 351 crore (vs. a loss of INR 971 crore in FY23).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B2C Business Dominates:&lt;/strong&gt;  The B2C business (Food Delivery, Quick Commerce, Going-Out) generated a combined GOV (Gross Order Value) of INR 47,918 crore, showing a 48% YoY growth. Adjusted Revenue from these segments was INR 10,351 crore.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food Delivery:&lt;/strong&gt; GOV grew by 23% YoY to INR 32,224 crore, while Adjusted Revenue grew by 27% YoY to INR 7,792 crore.  This segment achieved positive Adjusted EBITDA (INR 912 crore) for the full year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Commerce (Blinkit):&lt;/strong&gt;  GOV grew significantly by 93% YoY to INR 12,469 crore, indicating substantial growth in this segment. Adjusted Revenue increased by 116% YoY to INR 2,301 crore and reached Adjusted EBITDA breakeven in March 2024.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going-Out:&lt;/strong&gt; This segment, covering dining-out and ticketing, experienced explosive growth, with GOV surging 136% YoY to INR 3,225 crore. Adjusted Revenue grew 51% to INR 258 crore.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B2B Supplies (Hyperpure):&lt;/strong&gt;  Revenue grew by 111% YoY to INR 3,172 crore, driven by both core restaurant supplies and the expansion into quick commerce.  Adjusted EBITDA margin improved considerably to -4%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cash Position:&lt;/strong&gt; Consolidated cash balance increased to INR 12,241 crore as of March 24, 2024, indicating a strong financial position.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. Business Segments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
