<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>“Narayana Hrudayalaya Limited on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/narayana-hrudayalaya-limited/</link>
    <description>Recent content in “Narayana Hrudayalaya Limited on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/narayana-hrudayalaya-limited/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Narayana Hrudayalaya Limited: Q3 FY25 Earnings Call Transcript Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/narayana-hrudayalaya-limited2025-02-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/narayana-hrudayalaya-limited2025-02-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;financial-performance&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Financial Performance&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#financial-performance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue:&lt;/strong&gt; HCCI revenue is INR 293 crores. Combined revenue for Gurugram, Dharamshala, and SRCC is INR 130 crores.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Margins:&lt;/strong&gt; New hospitals (Gurugram, Dharamshala, SRCC) EBITDA margin is 6% (up from 3% in Q3 FY24). Dharamshala has a high double-digit EBITDA margin. Cayman margins saw recovery close to usual run rate on an EBITDA basis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gross Margin:&lt;/strong&gt; Strong gross margin due to consumption mix benefits and efficiencies from lean operations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Strategic Initiatives &amp;amp; Business Updates&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cayman Islands:&lt;/strong&gt; New hospital outpatient facility commissioned in December. Emergency room, inpatient surgeries commissioned from January 1st. Obstetrics and neonatal care to start mid-February. Integrated Care (insurance policies) sales started in Cayman from January 1st.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bahamas:&lt;/strong&gt; Small investment in the Bahamas.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;India Expansion:&lt;/strong&gt; Scouting for brownfield opportunities. Greenfield projects planned, with most projects fiscal &amp;lsquo;28 or beyond. Focus on expanding in Bangalore and Kolkata.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Health Clinics:&lt;/strong&gt; Target of 50 clinics in a year, moving into Kolkata. Launched Arya insurance plan (full outpatient, full inpatient). Expect INR 400-500 crores investment in the integrated care business.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mumbai:&lt;/strong&gt; Discussions with Trust to expand SRCC Hospital into a multi-specialty adult program.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Market &amp;amp; Competitive Landscape&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; Acknowledgment of Apollo and Max in the Gurgaon market.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry Trends:&lt;/strong&gt; Healthcare becoming unaffordable. Need to access more healthcare via insurance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medical Tourism:&lt;/strong&gt; Medical tourism from the U.S. to Cayman never materialized as expected.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Risk Factors &amp;amp; Challenges&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cayman Islands:&lt;/strong&gt; Difficulty in hiring new doctors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gurgaon Hospital:&lt;/strong&gt; Location limits catchment area.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expansion Delays:&lt;/strong&gt; Delays in negotiating contracts and licensing for expansion in India.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt Levels:&lt;/strong&gt; Potential for increased debt with project finance, targeting Debt-EBITDA levels up to 3.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Forward-Looking Statements&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cayman Islands:&lt;/strong&gt; Expect to commission all service lines by March. See Cayman growth in near quarters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;India:&lt;/strong&gt; Expect new units to perform better, with Gurugram leading improvement. Expect continued organic revenue growth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Health Clinics:&lt;/strong&gt; See clinics and insurance as an engine of growth for the integrated care business.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capex:&lt;/strong&gt; INR 400-500 crores investment in integrated care (clinics plus insurance). IRR target of upwards of 15% for projects.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividend Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; Consistent dividend strategy to continue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;qa-insights&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Q&amp;amp;A Insights&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#qa-insights&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bahamas Stake Acquisition:&lt;/strong&gt; The rationale for 4% acquisition is an initial step to increase that, to learn more about the market, or to see whether there is a potential to expand into the Bahamas.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acquisition Target:&lt;/strong&gt; A potential acquisition has to be in our core market: Bangalore or Kolkata, or second priority, Delhi or Raipur.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utilization of Cayman cash proceeds&lt;/strong&gt;: Investment in Bahamas is a key consideration, with the Indian market being the top priority.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Management Tone &amp;amp; Sentiment&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confident:&lt;/strong&gt; About the potential for synergies between Bahamas and Cayman.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pragmatic:&lt;/strong&gt; Acknowledging the difficulty in acquiring brownfield assets at the right price. Cautious about scaling up the clinic business too fast.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Committed:&lt;/strong&gt; To integrated care model and expanding primary health clinics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;button-container&#34;&gt;    &#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bseindia.com/xml-data/corpfiling/AttachHis/8638c8c1-2bb2-4026-9393-fec85bce55c1.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; class=&#34;report-button&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Download Transcript&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
