<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lloyds Engineering Works Ltd on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/lloyds-engineering-works-ltd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lloyds Engineering Works Ltd on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/lloyds-engineering-works-ltd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lloyds Engineering Works Ltd - Annual Report 2023-24 Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lloyds-engineering-works-ltd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lloyds-engineering-works-ltd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Overview&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Detailed Analysis&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#detailed-analysis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This analysis examines Lloyds Engineering Works Limited&amp;rsquo;s (LEWL) annual report for the fiscal year 2023-24, focusing on financial performance, business segments, identified risks, and ESG (Environmental, Social, and Governance) initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. Financial Performance:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LEWL experienced dramatic growth in FY24, a sharp turnaround from previous years. Key highlights include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Revenue Growth:&lt;/strong&gt;  Revenue from operations surged by 99.69% year-on-year (YoY) to ₹6,242.36 Lakhs (₹624.24 Crore), compared to ₹3,126.09 Lakhs (₹312.61 Crore) in FY23.  This represents a massive increase compared to the loss in FY22.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profitability Improvement:&lt;/strong&gt;  Profit After Tax (PAT) jumped by 116.82% YoY to ₹7,983.83 Lakhs (₹798.38 Crore), exceeding the FY22 turnover. Earnings Before Interest, Taxes, Depreciation, and Amortization (EBITDA) increased by 86.82% to ₹10,843.69 Lakhs (₹1,084.37 Crore).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Margins:&lt;/strong&gt;  EBITDA margin was 17.17%, slightly lower than the previous year&amp;rsquo;s 18.23%, but still high compared to industry averages. PAT margin was 12.64%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strong Order Book:&lt;/strong&gt; The order book increased significantly to ₹90,431.95 Lakhs (₹904.32 Crore), providing strong revenue visibility for the next 12-15 months.  This represents a 32.42% YoY growth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debt-Free Balance Sheet:&lt;/strong&gt; The company is debt-free, indicating strong financial health and stability.  Its net worth was ₹41,119.81 Lakhs (₹411.20 Crore) as of March 31, 2024.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Return on Equity (ROE):&lt;/strong&gt; ROE was a remarkable 26.32%, reflecting efficient capital utilization.  Return on Capital Employed (ROCE) was 22.12%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset Turnover:&lt;/strong&gt;  The company generated ₹8.11 for every rupee invested in gross block, indicating efficient asset utilization.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Capital Management:&lt;/strong&gt;  The company improved working capital management, reducing the working capital tenure and enhancing turnover.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. Business Segments:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
