<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Integrated Industries Limited on Financial Report Insights</title>
    <link>https://reports.muthu.co/tags/integrated-industries-limited/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Integrated Industries Limited on Financial Report Insights</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://reports.muthu.co/tags/integrated-industries-limited/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrated Industries Limited: Q3 FY25 Earnings Call Transcript Analysis</title>
      <link>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/integrated-industries-limited2025-02-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://reports.muthu.co/posts/integrated-industries-limited2025-02-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;earnings-call-transcript-analysis-report&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Earnings Call Transcript Analysis Report&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#earnings-call-transcript-analysis-report&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;financial-performance&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Financial Performance&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#financial-performance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue:&lt;/strong&gt; Cumulative revenue till now is Rs. 500-550 Crores types. FY25 revenue expected to close at approximately Rs 700 crores. FY26 expected revenue target of Rs. 1,000 crores. FY27 expected consolidated revenue approximately Rs 1,200 crores.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Margins:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintaining current margin levels is expected, with potential improvements from new premium product lines. Gross margins are approximately 20% and are at par with industry standards. Contract manufacturing maintains a gross margin of 12%-13%. Operating margin target of 15%-17% with the new premium segment products.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Expecting revenue to grow up by at least 50% in FY26. Expecting close to 70%-75% growth in sales in FY27.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The growth of around 35%-40% year-on-year will be there for the coming period.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;See, this year on a consolidated basis, if you see our revenue has increased many fold.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Strategic Initiatives &amp;amp; Business Updates&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#strategic-initiatives--business-updates&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expansion:&lt;/strong&gt; Setting up a new biscuit manufacturing facility to produce cookies and confectionery items. New manufacturing facility in Secunderabad, UP, with commercial production starting by the end of 2026, with a capacity of around 5000 tons. Land identified in Secunderabad for expansion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Development:&lt;/strong&gt; Developing healthier biscuit options, including low sugar, high fiber, and gluten-free variants. Proposing to introduce regional flavors and ingredients. Focusing on premium and value-added products such as cookies with added vitamins, minerals, or functional ingredients like probiotics. Plan to introduce lines for Danish Butter Cookies in the export market. Entering the confectionery business with wafer cones and chocolates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distribution Network:&lt;/strong&gt; Strengthening networks in rural and semi-urban areas. Expanding the distribution network beyond Northern India to parts of Eastern and Western India.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Presence:&lt;/strong&gt; Expanded global presence by establishing Nurture Well LLC in Dubai. Robust on the export market as US has put tariffs on biscuits from China. Received orders from the South American market.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have recently developed a range of healthier biscuit options, including low sugar, high fiber and gluten free variants to cater to the growing health conscious segment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are focusing on premium and value added products such as cookies with added vitamins, minerals or functional ingredients like probiotics which will expand into the international markets&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Market &amp;amp; Competitive Landscape&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#market--competitive-landscape&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry Growth:&lt;/strong&gt; Food industry FMCG market is growing at a rate of around 15%-20% year-on-year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competitive Advantage:&lt;/strong&gt; Strong distribution network of 150 plus business partners. Value-added product basket with high margins. Margins are better in our product as compared to the big companies. Extensive reachability, a diverse product range, and better margins compared to larger companies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;As you know that food industry FMCG market is growing at the rate of around 15%-20% year-on-year, so the demand cycle is always there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Risk Factors &amp;amp; Challenges&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#risk-factors--challenges&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No significant risks or challenges were explicitly stated in the provided transcript.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t foresee any major fluctuation happening in the raw material prices in 3-4 days.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Forward-Looking Statements&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#forward-looking-statements&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue Targets:&lt;/strong&gt; Targeting Rs. 1,000 figure in terms of topline in FY26. Consolidated revenue will be approximately Rs. 1,200 in FY27.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Production Commencement:&lt;/strong&gt; Commercial production in the new facility is expected by the end of 2026, with numbers reflecting in the balance sheet by 2027-28.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAPEX:&lt;/strong&gt; CAPEX of close to Rs. 400-Rs. 500 Cr is under consideration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profitability:&lt;/strong&gt; Expecting profits to go up by at least 30%-40%.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are expecting close to almost like 50% revenue will be coming from India and 50% revenue will be coming from overseas subsidiary.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;qa-insights&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Q&amp;amp;A Insights&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#qa-insights&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Analysts were keen on understanding the drivers of demand and growth momentum, expansion plans, geographical sales mix, cash collection cycle, capacity utilization, and funding for CAPEX.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Management highlighted the new manufacturing facility, expansion of the distribution network, new product ranges, and the strong distribution network as key growth drivers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Management addressed concerns about equity dilution and debt, emphasizing the company&amp;rsquo;s current debt-free status and the strategic use of funds for working capital and expansion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Management Tone &amp;amp; Sentiment&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#management-tone--sentiment&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Management displayed a confident tone regarding the company&amp;rsquo;s growth prospects and strategic initiatives. The emphasis on expansion, new product lines, and a strong distribution network indicates a positive outlook.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Management consistently reiterated the company&amp;rsquo;s debt-free status and the strategic use of funds for working capital and expansion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, we have got a very aggressive growth plan for the company.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;summary-of-key-takeaways&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Summary of Key Takeaways&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#summary-of-key-takeaways&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The earnings call highlighted Integrated Industries&amp;rsquo; aggressive growth strategy, driven by capacity expansion, new product development, and a strong distribution network. The company is targeting significant revenue growth in the coming years, with a focus on both domestic and international markets. While the company&amp;rsquo;s financial performance appears strong, further clarity on CAPEX funding and margin sustainability would be beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
